

Diana Rodrigues

I am a highly motivated, active and committed person in all the challenges I take on. In the two years of experience, I was able to design and carry out experiments, test drugs, research scientific literature and write technical reports. I have excellent analytical and communication skills and a dedicated approach to working in a highly controlled work environment. I like to develop new tools to improve people's lives and learn more. In recent years, I have been working in the chemistry area, more precisely in academy research. However, I didn't develop my skills as I wanted and therefore I decided to change my career recently. I started by taking a course in Web Development area and I enjoyed working with these technologies. So, I am looking for a new challenge for my career and for my personal and professional growth.

Contact

Mobile:

(+351) 918079591

Email:

dianarsrodrigues@gmail.com

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/dianarsrodrigues

GitHub:

github.com/dianarsrodrigues

Languages Spoken

Portuguese:

Native

English:

Intermediate (B1)

Spanish:



Intermediate (B1)

Digital skills

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- C - Shell
- Bootstrap 4
- Javascript ES6
- DOM Manipulation
- jQuery
- Bash Command Line
- Git, GitHub and Version Control
- Node.js
- Express.js
- APIs

Work Experience

Research Fellowship

LAQV/REQUIMTE, ORCHIDS Unit, Faculty of Sciences of the University of Porto | October 2021 - June 2022

- Synthesis of ligands for functionalization of nanosystems and development of nanoformulations with encapsulated anti-tuberculosis drugs as well as their physicochemical characterization. *In vitro* and *in vivo* studies of the developed formulations towards the treatment of tuberculosis.

Research Fellowship

LAQV/REQUIMTE, ORCHIDS Unit, Faculty of Sciences of the University of Porto | September 2020 - February 2021

- Synthesis of serine-derived gemini surfactants, physicochemical characterization and study of compounds developed as potential antimicrobial agents.

Junior University Monitor

University of Porto | July 2019

- Activity monitor: Chemistry in action (Summer in project)

Education

The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp

Online course | March 2023 - Present

In the end of this course I was capable to build ANY website you want.

Main skills acquired:

HTML • CSS • Logic programming • JavaScript • Node

42 School - Programming School

Porto November 2022 - Present

Programming course in a peer-to-peer learning model, through out the course I learned the C language, C++ and Shell with colleagues from different areas, in the discovery of new skills in the programming area.

Main skills acquired:

 $\textbf{Teamwork} \bullet \textbf{C} \text{ (programming language)} \bullet \textbf{Logic programming} \bullet \textbf{Shell script} \bullet \textbf{Peer support}$

Responsive Web Design

Online course | October 2022

In the end of this course I was capable to build a website from scratch with HTML and CSS. Main skills acquired:

HTML • CSS

Build Websites from Scratch with HTML & CSS

Online course | August 2022

In the end of this course I was capable to build a website from scratch with HTML, CSS and a little of JavaScript.

Main skills acquired:

HTML • CSS • Logic programming • JavaScript

Master in Pharmaceutical Chemistry

Faculty of Pharmacy of the University of Porto | September 2019 - October 2021

Master's Dissertation in Pharmaceutical Chemistry developed in the areas of Medicinal Chemistry and Microbiology - "Gemini surfactants derived from serine: synthesis, characterization, and application".

Degree in Chemistry

Faculty of Sciences of the University of Porto | September 2016 - July 2019

Bachelor's degree project in Chemistry developed in the area of Medicinal Chemistry - "Síntese de novas classes de tensioativos derivados de serina como potenciais agentes antimicrobianos".